echonest.com 2018-12-24

# Privacy | The Echo Nest

## Echo Nest Privacy Policy

(Last Revised 1/22/13)

The Echo Nest is committed to informing you about our use of information gathered by our personalization, information and data services and your privacy options. This privacy policy applies to all The Echo Nest products and services worldwide that display or link to this notice. The purpose of this privacy policy is to give you information about the information we collect, how we use that information, and inform you of your choices with respect to the collection and use of data. 

### **About Our Online Personalization and Data Services**

We do not collect personally identifiable information (“PII”). PII is information that can be used to contact or identify a natural person. Examples of PII include, but are not limited to: name, email address, postal address, telephone number, social security number, and credit card number.

The Echo Nest analyzes non-PII activity data for our customers and partners to enable personalized music recommendations and actionable insights to improve the performance of our customers’ and partners’ music services and also advertising campaigns, including targeting ads. All of this data is anonymous, meaning that we do not associate it with personally-identifiable information.

### **The Non-Personal Information We Collect**

Our partners and customers collect information for our ad targeting services through the use of common internet technologies, such as cookies and web beacons, on the web sites or devices or in web widgets or other embedded functions. Cookies are small text files that can be used by a web site to store information on a users' machine and later retrieve it. Our privacy statement does not cover the use of cookies by our partners, affiliates, tracking utility company, or service providers. We do not have access or control over these cookies. Our partners, affiliates, tracking utility company, service providers may use their own cookies to personalize a user experience or in some cases to deliver personalized commercial offerings or advertisements in some cases, based on musical information provided in aggregate form from the Echo Nest. Neither we nor our partners store any personally identifiable information in the cookies. 

### **Information Security and Retention**

The Echo Nest uses a variety of technologies and procedures to protect information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. While we have taken commercially reasonable efforts to guard information, we cannot guarantee that it will not be disclosed or accessed by accidental circumstances or by the unauthorized acts of others. 

Non-PII data collected by The Echo Nest for ad targeting purposes is generally retained indefinitely or for a shorter period as stipulated by the agreements we have with our customers. 

### **Choices**

You may choose to opt out from our partners directly through the Network Advertising Initiative's Consumer Opt-Out Program. Since the NAI Opt-Out Program is cookie-based, you may need to opt out again (and set a new "opt-out" cookie) if you do any of the following: delete your cookies, switch Internet browsers, change computers, or upgrade your web browser. Our partners that are online music services may have their own mechanisms for opting out from our anonymous data collection for use in our ad targeting services. 

### **Personally Identifiable Information You Provide to Us through our Corporate Website**

We only collect personally identifiable information when we are contacted directly by an individual through our web site and the individual provides that personally identifying information to us. That information may include name, email address or phone number or other information that the user may choose to provide. 

We use this information to respond to these requests or inquiries. We do not provide this information to third parties.

We do not use this personal information for our online behavioral advertising services. Anyone who has provided personal contact information through The Echo Nest web site may send e-mail to personalinformation@echonest.com to update, delete, and/or correct their personal contact information. The Echo Nest will respond to such a request within thirty (30) days of the date the request is submitted. 

### **Safe Harbor Compliance**

The Echo Nest complies with the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland. The Echo Nest has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view our certification, please visit http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/

For complaints and disputes that cannot be resolved between The Echo Nest and the complainant, The Echo Nest has agreed to participate in the dispute resolution procedures of the panel established by the EU data protection authorities (DPAs) to resolve disputes pursuant to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles, as well as to cooperate and comply with the Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner of Switzerland. The panel may be contacted at ec-dppanel-secr@ec.europa.eu and individual EU DPAs may be contacted directly via the information provided at http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/bodies/authorities/eu/index_en.htm. The contact information for the Swiss FDPIC can be found at: http://www.edoeb.admin.ch/kontakt/index.html?lang=en.
